[
    {
        "cat": "jobs",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Both Clinton and Trump want to raise the minimum wage, which in Texas is …?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "$5.15/hr",
                    "$7.25/hr",
                    "$10/hr",
                    "$15/hr"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "$7.25/hr",
                "explainer": "Since Texas does not have a minimum wage, the state defaults to the federal wage rate which today is $7.25 an hour."
            },
            {
                "question": "How many states already have a minimum wage that’s higher than Texas?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "8",
                    "15",
                    "23",
                    "29"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "29",
                "explainer": "Twenty-nine states and the District of Columbia have raised their minimum wage above the wage set by the federal government. Some have set the minimum wage as high as $10/hr."
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the average per capita personal income in Texas?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "$22.987",
                    "$35,550",
                    "$46,745",
                    "$75,904"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "$46,745",
                "explainer": "In 2015, Texas had an annual average per capita income of $46,745, which ranks 22nd among the states."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "cat": "healthcare",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Both Trump and Clinton want to improve the care offered to the nation’s veterans. What is the health insurance program offered to active duty and retired military service members called?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "Tricare",
                    "MiliCare",
                    "Obamacare",
                    "Medicare"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "Tricare",
                "explainer": "The Defense Health Agency runs Tricare for members of the military, military retirees and their families. In Texas, Tricare has 881,560 beneficiaries, or 9.4 percent of the total."
            },
            {
                "question": "According to estimates from the U.S. Census, what percentage of the U.S. population was uninsured in 2015?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "15.9 percent",
                    "19.2 percent",
                    "45 percent",
                    "56.5 percent"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "15.9 percent",
                "explainer": "The latest figure from the Census estimated that about 15.9 percent of Americans are without insurance. But more recent polling indicates the percentage has fallen to around 11 percent."
            },
            {
                "question": "While Texas has not expanded Medicaid, under Obamacare rules the federal government pays if states expand Medicaid to people earning up to 138 percent of the poverty level, which for a family of four is …",
                "answer_group": [
                    "$14,550 a year",
                    "$25,890 a year",
                    "$33,534 a year",
                    "$55,779 a year"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "$33,534 a year",
                "explainer": "Texas is among 19 states that have not expanded Medicaid to include this group. It is estimated that between 750,000 and 1 million Texans could be covered if Texas expanded Medicaid."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "cat": "trade",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "The proposed Trans-Pacific Partnership, which both candidates say they oppose, notably excludes what economic powerhouse?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "China",
                    "Japan",
                    "Australia",
                    "Vietnam"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "China",
                "explainer": "The 12-nation pact does not include China, the dominant player in the region. President Obama has billed TPP as a way to counter China’s outsized influence. But China could still join TPP at a later date."
            },
            {
                "question": "The North American Free Trade Agreement, which is a free-trade pact between Canada, the United States and Mexico went into effect on January 1 of what year?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "1977",
                    "1980",
                    "1994",
                    "2000"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "1994",
                "explainer": "President Bill Clinton signed the law on Dec.8. 1993, and it went into effect a few weeks later."
            },
            {
                "question": "A tax on goods leaving a country or coming into a country is called ...?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "An excise tax",
                    "A value-added tax",
                    "A bond",
                    "A tariff"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "A tariff",
                "explainer": "Tariffs can be used by governments seeking to protect domestic industries, but they often provoke other countries to impose their own tariffs."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "cat": "energy",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Trump and Clinton disagree on whether there should be more federal regulations on this drilling technique that has led to a boom in Texas oil and gas production.",
                "answer_group": [
                    "Fracking",
                    "Milling",
                    "Mudding up",
                    "Weathering"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "Fracking",
                "explainer": "While Clinton would support a ban on fracking, Trump has said he is in favor of it but would support local bans."
            },
            {
                "question": "On renewable energy, Texas has more installed wind power capacity than any other state. Which state is number two?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "South Dakota",
                    "California",
                    "Iowa",
                    "New York"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "Iowa",
                "explainer": "According to the 2015 annual report by the American Wind Energy Association, Texas continues to lead the nation with over 17,700 megawatts of installed capacity. Iowa ranks second in the nation with more than 6,200 MW of installed capacity, passing California."
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a fossil fuel?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "Coal",
                    "Oil",
                    "Natural gas",
                    "Nuclear"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "Nuclear",
                "explainer": "Clinton’s policies would reduce the nation’s reliance on fossil fuels, which include coal, oil and natural gas. Trump has said he will support these industries and the jobs they produce."
            }
        ]
    }
    ,{
        "cat": "taxes",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "For Tax Year 2014, how many federal income tax returns filed in Texas reported adjusted gross income of more than $1 million?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "15,990",
                    "38,840",
                    "75,299",
                    "100,854"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "38,840",
                "explainer": "According the the IRS, there were 38,840 income tax returns from Texas that reported $1 million or more in income.  That doesn’t include those who have $1 million or more in assets."
            },
            {
                "question": "For Tax Year 2014, how much did individual filers from Texas send to the federal government?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "$5 billion",
                    "$29 billion",
                    "$130 billion",
                    "$345 billion"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "$130 billion",
                "explainer": "According to the IRS, Texans sent $130 billion to the federal government from individual income tax returns."
            },
            {
                "question": "For Fiscal Year 2015, what percentage of the taxes that Texas sent to the federal government were from corporate income taxes?",
                "answer_group": [
                    "11.5 percent",
                    "15.9 percent",
                    "25.2 percent",
                    "50.8 percent"
                ],
                "correct_answer": "11.5 percent",
                "explainer": "While taxes on individuals, both income and payroll taxes, from Texas made up nearly 80 percent of what the state sent to Washington, taxes on corporations made up 11.5 percent."
            }
        ]
    }
]
